<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic | My Site</title>
    <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/tags/academic/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ovezovm.github.io/tags/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academic</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ovezovm.github.io/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/tags/academic/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (August 24-31)</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;celebrating-milestones&#34;&gt;Celebrating Milestones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week ended on a high note! After weeks of hard work, we finally hit a major milestone. The system passed load testing with flying colors, and the performance is now well within acceptable limits. My team and I had a small celebration at the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I feel a great sense of accomplishment. From struggling with Docker and bugs to optimizing performance, this project has pushed me to improve my skills in many areas. Now we’re moving into the next phase — deploying the system to production. There’s still a lot to do, but I’m more confident than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (June 15-22)</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;refactoring-frenzy&#34;&gt;Refactoring Frenzy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After resolving most of the bugs last week, I realized the codebase had become quite messy. So this week was dedicated to refactoring. I reorganized several modules, cleaned up redundant code, and implemented a more consistent logging system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was tedious work, but very satisfying. Seeing the code become more modular and easier to maintain is always rewarding. I also wrote additional unit tests to ensure future changes won’t break anything unexpectedly. Now the code is in much better shape, and I’m confident it’ll be easier to scale and extend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (June 23-30)</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unexpected-challenges&#34;&gt;Unexpected Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week threw me a curveball. I encountered a serious performance issue during load testing. The system was much slower than expected under heavy traffic. After analyzing the logs, I found that one of the services was causing bottlenecks due to inefficient database queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent days optimizing those queries, indexing database tables, and implementing caching mechanisms. By the end of the week, the performance improved significantly, but I still feel there’s room for further optimization. It’s been stressful, but I’ve learned a lot about performance tuning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (March 11-17)</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-social-aspect&#34;&gt;The social aspect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;his week started with excitement. I was assigned a new project at work, which involves building a microservice architecture using Python and Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;favorite-activity&#34;&gt;Favorite activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked with monolithic systems before, so diving into microservices is both a challenge and an opportunity for growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent most of the week studying different design patterns, ensuring scalability and resilience in the system. There were moments of frustration, especially when Docker containers wouldn’t behave as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-result&#34;&gt;The result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, by the end of the week, I managed to get a working prototype of one service. It’s just the beginning, but I’m looking forward to the coming weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (May 22-28)</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-exhibition&#34;&gt;Another exhibition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week turned out to be intense. After setting up the initial prototype last week, I started integrating the different services. And guess what? Bugs everywhere! The communication between services wasn’t as smooth as I had anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;study&#34;&gt;Study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent hours debugging issues related to network calls between Docker containers and configuring the message broker correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-result&#34;&gt;The result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were days when I felt like I was chasing ghosts in the code, but slowly things started to make sense. By Friday, I finally managed to fix the majority of the communication issues, and the system is now running more smoothly&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
