<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic | My Site</title>
    <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/tags/academic/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ovezovm.github.io/tags/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academic</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ovezovm.github.io/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/tags/academic/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (August 24-31)</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sad&#34;&gt;Sad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These months at home have passed too quickly. It seemed that he had just met with his family, hugged his parents, sat with friends, and it was time to return to school. It&amp;rsquo;s so strange to realize that you have to leave everything that is so dear again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every corner here is saturated with memories, and every day the departure seems harder. I will miss evenings with my loved ones and walking along familiar streets. Of course, there are new knowledge and opportunities ahead, but leaving home is always difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (June 15-22)</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;coming-home&#34;&gt;Coming home&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I finally returned to my homeland. I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for this moment for a long time, and it exceeded all expectations. As soon as I got off the plane, I was overcome by a feeling of something native, familiar. The air, the smells, even the noise of the streets — everything reminded of childhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;upon-arrival&#34;&gt;Upon arrival&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did was go to my parents. They greeted me with warm hugs and joy in their eyes. We talked for a long time, remembering the old days. Mom cooked her favorite dishes, and at dinner we laughed like in the good old days. The house I grew up in seemed the same, but it felt like a new comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;old-friends&#34;&gt;Old friends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I met with friends. We all changed — someone got a job, someone got a family, but as soon as we got together, everything was exactly the same as many years ago. We walked along the old streets for a long time, laughing and sharing stories. It turned out that time could not destroy our friendship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-result&#34;&gt;The result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am glad that I was able to return and feel connected to my native places and people again. This week reminded me that roots are an important part of life, and no matter how far you go, home is always waiting for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (June 23-30)</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;briefly&#34;&gt;Briefly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I am still at home, the past week is not really different from the last one, which can be found in the previous post. I visited relatives who do not live near us, saw many more friends and helped my parents with the housework.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (March 11-17)</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-social-aspect&#34;&gt;The social aspect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week has been eventful and filled with a variety of impressions. I plunged into the world of art and culture by attending several interesting events. Each of them gave new emotions, reflections and inspiration. Live performances and galleries helped me disconnect from the daily hustle and bustle and rethink the usual things a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reunion&#34;&gt;Reunion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the middle of the week, I went home to my parents. These trips always bring a special feeling of peace and comfort. The homely atmosphere and native faces are a real reboot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;favorite-activity&#34;&gt;Favorite activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I ended the week on my favorite note — horseback riding. There is nothing better than riding through the fields, feeling freedom and harmony with nature. The time spent with my beloved horses was the perfect point at the end of this busy week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-result&#34;&gt;The result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good that there are such moments!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week&#39;s post (May 22-28)</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/nedelniy-post-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-exhibition&#34;&gt;Another exhibition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past week has been eventful and memorable. It began with a trip to the exhibition, where I was impressed not only by the works of contemporary artists, but also by the atmosphere of art in general. It was great to see how art affects the perception of the world around us, and to leave with new thoughts and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rest&#34;&gt;Rest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, towards the middle of the week, I went fishing with friends. It was a great way to relax and get away from the hustle and bustle of the city. We enjoyed nature, talked around the campfire, and a few caught fish became a pleasant bonus. Time spent outdoors always gives you a boost of energy and positive emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;study&#34;&gt;Study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the week was not without study. I continued to work on important topics, trying not to lose pace. Studying took a lot of time, but each new step I took made me more confident in my knowledge. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to feel progress and realize that all the efforts are worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-result&#34;&gt;The result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended the week with a full rest, allowing myself to relax and enjoy the silence. At such moments, you realize how important it is to be able to recover and find a balance between work, study and personal interests. It was the perfect end to a week filled with different events and emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
