<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Site</title>
    <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ovezovm.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>My Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ovezovm.github.io/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>My Site</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post for the week from April 22 to 28</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/summary3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/summary3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;third-post&#34;&gt;Third post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is a demo where I demonstrate that I have figured out how to work with posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;events-of-the-week&#34;&gt;Events of the week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week passed as usual. No deviations from normality were recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-of-numbering&#34;&gt;Example of numbering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;second item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/publication/bib/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/publication/bib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working with Bibliography: Your Key to Successful Research!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure where to start your research project or essay? Introducing your essential tool – the bibliography. It’s not just a list of sources, but a true guide in the world of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a bibliography? It is a list of literary sources used or recommended for a particular project. A properly compiled bibliography not only enhances your work but also confirms its credibility and serious approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few important rules to remember when working with a bibliography:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thorough analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: Critically evaluate each source. Make sure it aligns with your topic and is reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization&lt;/strong&gt;: Arrange your sources according to a format, be it MLA, APA, or another standard. This will make your bibliography more readable and professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completeness and accuracy&lt;/strong&gt;: Don’t forget to include all the sources you used, even if you only mentioned them in the text. Also, ensure all details are correct—from the book title to the URL link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevance&lt;/strong&gt;: Give preference to recent sources. It’s best to use materials published within the last five years, especially when it comes to scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respect for authors&lt;/strong&gt;: Always credit all authors with full awareness of their contribution to your research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bibliography is not only a requirement for the format of your project but also your chance to demonstrate a deep understanding of the topic and respect for the work of other scholars. Use this tool wisely, and it will open the doors to an infinite world of knowledge! 🚀📖&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post for the week from April 1 to 7</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/summary2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/summary2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-post&#34;&gt;First post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is an example where I demonstrate that I figured out how to work with posts 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;events-of-the-week&#34;&gt;Events of the week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week passed as usual. No deviations from normality were recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-of-numbering&#34;&gt;Example of numbering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week there was a midterm in mathematical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week there was a test in discrete mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post for the week from March 11 to 17</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/summary1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/post/summary1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-post&#34;&gt;First post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is a demo where I demonstrate that I have figured out how to work with posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;events-of-the-week&#34;&gt;Events of the week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week passed as usual. No deviations from normality were recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-of-numbering&#34;&gt;Example of numbering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;second item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grandeur of Markup Languages</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/publication/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/publication/latex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Markup languages are the frameworks upon which beautiful and informative documents are built. Among them stands LaTeX, which not only provides an aesthetically pleasing appearance but also offers powerful capabilities for creating complex textual documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is LaTeX?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LaTeX is a high-quality document preparation system originally developed by Leslie Lamport in the late 1970s. It is based on the TeX markup language, created by Donald Knuth. LaTeX offers a wide range of tools for creating professionally formatted scientific, technical, and mathematical documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages of LaTeX:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional Appearance&lt;/strong&gt;: LaTeX automatically formats documents, ensuring proper placement of text, images, tables, and equations. This allows the creation of documents with a high-quality appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mathematical Capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;: LaTeX is the standard for writing mathematical formulas and equations. Thanks to its powerful mathematical markup system, LaTeX makes it easy to create complex mathematical documents, including scientific articles and educational materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-Platform&lt;/strong&gt;: LaTeX is available on all popular operating systems and compatible with various text editors. This makes it a convenient choice for a wide range of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extensibility&lt;/strong&gt;: With packages and styles, users can extend the functionality of LaTeX and customize it to their needs. This allows the creation of unique and individualized documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LaTeX remains a consistently popular tool among the academic and scientific community due to its powerful capabilities and professional appearance. Despite the learning curve for beginners, the efforts invested in mastering LaTeX pay off in the form of high-quality documents and efficient text handling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version Control. Git.</title>
      <link>https://ovezovm.github.io/publication/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ovezovm.github.io/publication/git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;version-control-system&#34;&gt;Version Control System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version Control System&lt;/strong&gt; is a tool used to track, apply, and manage changes in code. It can also simply be called version control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control systems help developers save the changes made to a file at different stages so that both they and their colleagues can view them later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three types of version control systems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local version control systems \&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Centralized version control systems \&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distributed version control systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-git&#34;&gt;What is Git?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt; is a free and open-source distributed version control system that can be used to track changes in your files. With Git, you can work on all types and sizes of projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Git, you can add changes to your code and commit (or save) them when necessary. This means you can always revert to previous changes. Git works hand in hand with GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-github&#34;&gt;What is GitHub?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt; is a web interface where you can store your Git repositories and efficiently track and manage your changes. It allows different developers to access the code of a single project. You can make your own changes to a project simultaneously with other developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you make a mistake while making changes, you can easily return to the previous stage where no error occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;git-principles&#34;&gt;Git Principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working with Git, developers usually follow three principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commit regularly — save changes in Git frequently. This will allow for a more detailed version history and help identify errors quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create new branches. They make it easy to manage changes, especially parallel ones. It&amp;rsquo;s better to create a new branch than to mess up the old one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly and concisely describe commits. The code changes sent to Git must contain explanations and comments on the added edits and improvements. This greatly simplifies collaboration and helps in understanding old code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-git-commands&#34;&gt;Main Git Commands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git version control is a command-line program that represents a distributed version control system, meaning each developer has their own copy of the repository with the full history of changes. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider the main commands for working with Git.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several basic Git commands that every developer should know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git config&lt;/code&gt; - this command is used to set the username, email address, and user branch to determine who made the changes while working on the project. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git init&lt;/code&gt; - this command is used to initialize Git in your project to track changes made to the project. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote add origin&lt;/code&gt; - sets the origin for our repository, where we store our code in the cloud. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add&lt;/code&gt; - this command adds your file to the staging area. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git commit&lt;/code&gt; - this command commits any file that was added using the &lt;code&gt;git add&lt;/code&gt; command, as well as all files in the staging area. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone&lt;/code&gt; - this command is used to copy an existing repository from one place to another. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt; - this command is used to upload/send files from a local repository/storage to another storage, such as a remote one like GitHub. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git rm&lt;/code&gt; - this command is used to remove a file from the working repository. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git branch&lt;/code&gt; - this command is used to check the current branch you&amp;rsquo;re working on, main or master. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git diff&lt;/code&gt; - Git will show you the difference between the current code and the code when it was last saved. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git log&lt;/code&gt; - we can view the commits we have made. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git checkout&lt;/code&gt; - go back and see the changes in our code from a previous commit. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git merge&lt;/code&gt; - will take all the commits you made in this branch and insert them into the main branch, preserving your work. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git status&lt;/code&gt; – check the status of commits (their number, changes made).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
